# EVAN KURNIAWAN

FREMONT, CA 94536

(510) 585 5712 evanz\_ho@ymail.com www.linkedin.com/in/evankurniawan

### PROFILE

I am a natural at solving problems and acquiring information to make things better. With a can-do attitude, I am capable of prioritizing and organizing tasks to meet tight deadlines.

I am an experienced System Administrator and IT Support with a demonstrated history of working in the IT industry.

### **EDUCATION**

MASTER OF COMPUTER NETWORK AND COMMUNICATIONS MANAGEMENT DeVry University | 2012-2014

**BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE** Binus University | 2000-2004

CISCO CERTIFIED NETWORK ASSOCIATE (CCNA)

## WORK AUTHORIZATION

Visa Sponsorship Not Required



### EXPERIENCE

### **NETWORK SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR**

### New Pacific Direct, Inc. (Newark, CA) | Feb 2015 - Present

- Oversee network security, communication & internet design.
- Diagnose, troubleshoot and resolve network systems problem.
- Perform data backups and disaster recovery operations.
- Oversee ongoing maintenance of the Company's telecommunications and computer systems.
- Configure and manage IPSec and SSL VPN between partners and remote
- Support and manage HQ and branch offices wireless networks.
- Plan and executes installation, configuration, testing, and upgrades of routers, switches, and firewalls.
- Administer and troubleshoot Office 365.
- Setup Active Directory domain and forest trust.
- Manage internal and external DNS.

### **IT SUPPORT**

# 2012 DeVry University (Fremont, CA) | 2012 - 2015

- Monitoring and maintaining computer systems and networks, installs and configures hardware and software.
- Troubleshoot system and network problems, diagnosing and solving hardware or software faults.
- Administrate infrastructure, including firewalls, databases, malware protection software and other processes.
- Setup a VoIP Phone System for remote offices.
- Deploy, manage, and troubleshoot Wireless network company and guest network.
- Review troubled/aged ticket reports and prioritize tickets for follow-up.
- Monitor tickets that are initiated by VIP users.

### **SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR**

# 2008 IEE (Singapore) | 2008 - 2012

- Maintain and administer computer networks and related computing environments,
- Provide technical support for both hardware and software issues our users encounter.
- Setup, manage, and troubleshoot remote access points, private network, VPN (IPsec and SSL), and connectivity issues.
- Respond to and resolve help desk requests.
- · Create and verify backups of data.
- Setup and manage McAfee Virus Scan Enterprise, Windows Firewall.
- Perform escalated diagnosis, support, and resolution of complex incidents and service requests.

## 2005

### **DESKTOP SUPPORT**

### IBM (Singapore) | 2005 - 2008

- Develop and maintain training materials for Help Desk agents
- Install, configure and troubleshoot user software on Windows desktops and
- Perform escalated diagnosis, support, and resolution of complex incidents and service requests.
- Review troubled/aged ticket reports and prioritize tickets for follow-up.
- Assist Technician with diagnosis, support, and resolution of incidents and service requests during periods of peak demand.
- Review troubled/aged ticket reports and prioritize tickets for follow-up.
- · Assist Technician with diagnosis, support, and resolution of incidents and service requests during periods of peak demand.



### SKILLS

Operating Systems: MS Windows, Mac OS, Linux, Chrome OS Network: TCP/IP, DHCP, DNS, VoIP Phone, VPN, Firewall, Hyper-V,

Active Directory, Cisco Router & Switch.

Software Application: Office 365, Knowbe4, ERP, Acronis

Ticketing Software: Zendesk, JIRA

SaaS CRM: Hubspot

Product Experience Management (PRX): Salsify, Plytix

Language: C, C++, HTML

Microsoft Suite: Outlook, Word, Excel, Publisher Google Suite: Gmail, Docs, Sheets, Calendar Adobe Creative Suite: Photoshop, Premiere Pro